‪-To be really honest with you…
‪-Yeah.
‪I'm saying this because it's just us here.
‪After filming the show…
‪I had a really hard time.
‪-Why?
‪-Emotionally, that is.
‪Do you remember
‪how you came back to me
‪and chose me during the final selection?
‪I thought it was because you wanted to
‪clean up your image at the end.
‪To be honest, all the women shared
‪how the dates went.
‪And I heard things too, you know?
‪So when I put that all together,
‪I came to the conclusion
‪that you had lost interest in me.
‪I thought you were worried
‪you might get some backlash
‪once the show aired
‪and selected me perfunctorily.
‪But this is…
‪This is a huge misunderstanding.
‪If that's what I had thought,
‪I wouldn't have gone on dates like that.
‪What do you mean?
‪If I'd been so worried
‪about how I'd look on TV,
‪I wouldn't have gone on so many dates.
‪I mean, it's better to appear devoted.
‪Right?
‪I guess so.
‪But still,
‪I was much more open about my feelings
‪than I usually would be,
‪and because of that,
‪I thought I had made my feelings
‪very clear to you.
‪Regardless of whether
‪your feelings for me were sincere or not,
‪I just wanted to follow my heart,
‪which was why you were my final selection.
‪But afterward,
‪I didn't want to continue
‪since I thought you weren't interested.
‪Everything's falling into place now.
‪Do you remember
‪-when we talked on KakaoTalk?
‪-Yes.
‪And you said,
‪"I knew you wouldn't reach out to me…"
‪-Something like that.
‪-Right.
‪I thought you wouldn't message me.
‪Right, so I felt puzzled
‪because I didn't exactly know
‪what you were thinking.
‪I had no idea that's how you felt.
‪It's embarrassing to say this,
‪but I have a lot of pride.
‪-Right.
‪-And I'm a bit defensive.
‪I need to have
‪complete control over everything
‪-not to get stressed.
‪-Right.
‪But you can't control emotions.
‪So I slowly gave myself closure.
‪THEIR TRUE FEELINGS GOT LOST
‪IN MISUNDERSTANDING
‪But didn't you have
‪a similar misunderstanding?
‪Yes, I did too. Because as for me…
‪I heard all about it.
‪As for me,
‪whenever we were on a date,
‪you kept worrying about
‪"What if it comes off this way
‪or that way on air?"
‪I did?
‪So I didn't think
‪you were truly interested in me.
‪At the time,
‪I thought I wasn't your priority.
‪It's going to be on TV.
‪Isn't it natural to be worried?
‪But I was being genuine at all times.
‪You've never once been
‪at the bottom of my list of priorities.
‪Then again, I thought
‪you weren't interested in me…
‪Right, it's clicking for me now…
‪So I figured I'd just be open
‪with you today
‪since it's already over between us.
‪I can see where you're coming from.
‪But when the others told me
‪about what you said,
‪I realized I might've misunderstood you.
‪And I thought maybe
‪it was the same for you.
‪I just realized why the writer told me
‪to have a one-on-one with you.
‪-Right.
‪-Yeah.
‪It's a real shame
‪when I think about it now.
‪Yeah.
‪If we had talked sooner,
‪our misunderstandings
‪wouldn't have lasted so long.
‪We should've talked sooner.
‪I know.
‪I really want to date.
‪It's so important to me.
‪I don't care about being on TV.
‪Just getting to meet men is
‪such a huge deal for me.
‪It really is a rare opportunity.
‪I'm really hoping to find someone.
‪But I do want to fall in love.
‪I want to find love.
‪If I could find love
‪through this good opportunity,
‪I'd be over the moon.
‪This might sound a bit dramatic, but…
‪Well…
‪I really wanted
‪to experience
‪a healthy and ideal relationship.
‪I really wanted that.
‪But I believed to do that,
‪trust is key.
‪Right, I agree.
‪That was my reason too.
‪That's what I believed,
‪so I felt we had to spend time in Seoul,
‪not in Eternal Singles' Village.
‪If I were to contact you…
‪-We never met up outside.
‪-Right.
‪We only saw each other in the village
‪surrounded by cameras.
‪So if we met outside and…
‪I don't know how to say this.
‪I wondered if you'd be okay
‪if I just acted more like myself.
‪-You know what I mean?
‪-Yeah.
‪Well…
‪I think we continue this in private.
‪It's a woody fragrance.
‪It smells nice.
‪So you like perfume.
‪Yes, I really like perfume.
‪Me too.
‪I think we had a lot in common.
‪I'm a curator.
‪I've always liked exhibitions.
‪Is this fate?
‪I thought, "That might be the case."
‪What?
‪-Did you pick Agungi Tea Room?
‪-Yes.
‪Seriously.
‪It's so fascinating. Are you serious?
‪I got matched with him again.
‪I couldn't believe it.
‪Whose is this?
‪It's mine.
‪They say repeated coincidences mean fate.
‪That's right.
‪-But this feels like fate.
‪-Fate?
‪I feel like we had
‪a special connection from the start.
‪We got really lucky
‪since we kept getting matched on dates.
‪I decided to call it fate.
‪Q. DO YOU STILL BELIEVE IN FATE?
‪Yes, I still do.
‪I think there's a certain connection
‪that draws people to each other.
‪To be honest, I believe in fate too.
‪Q. WHAT'S NEXT FOR YOU TWO?
‪I think
‪that's something fate will decide for us.
‪AFTER THE FINAL COUPLE TALKS
‪WE ARRANGED A SPECIAL GATHERING
‪FOR THE ETERNAL SINGLES
‪What's that notebook?
‪Maybe we're writing something.
‪Like a letter?
‪What's this for?
‪Do we have to write something?
‪I want to keep this.
‪We're writing something?
‪I don't know.
‪Maybe they'll ask questions.
‪A SPECIAL SEMINAR
‪FOR THE ETERNAL SINGLES STILL OUT THERE
‪What?
‪-We need to take notes?
‪-It's for note-taking?
‪Note-taking?
‪A SPECIAL SEMINAR
‪FOR THE ETERNAL SINGLES STILL OUT THERE
‪IF YOU TAKE THIS SEMINAR
‪HEY, YOU CAN DATE TOO!
‪"Hey, you can date too!"
‪PLEASE WELCOME OUR DATING EXPERT
‪WITH A BIG ROUND OF APPLAUSE!
‪Wow.
‪"Time to Change Eternal Singles."
‪You're right.
‪-"Time to Change Eternal Singles."
‪-I knew it'd be like that show.
‪-Who is it?
‪Who's coming?
‪TODAY'S SPEAKER
‪FOR THE ETERNAL SINGLES
‪Who could it be?
‪-Who is it?
‪-Who's coming?
‪-Wow.
‪-Hey!
‪-Wow!
‪Gosh!
‪It's Jae-yun.
‪-Wow.
‪-Amazing!
‪SENIOR ETERNAL SINGLE
‪NOH JAE-YUN
‪I really want to date.
‪ETERNAL SINGLE JAE-YUN
‪REALLY WANTED TO DATE
‪BUT ESCAPING ETERNAL SINGLEDOM
‪WASN'T SMOOTH SAILING
‪I kept tearing up.
‪STUCK IN A CYCLE OF TEARS AND MISTAKES
‪HE BECAME THE ETERNAL SINGLE IN THE BUSHES
‪BUT AFTERWARD…
‪I'll keep trying my best to be a good man.
‪"BLTS" JAE-YUN ESCAPES ETERNAL SINGLEDOM
‪"BLTS" JAE-YUN IN A RELATIONSHIP
‪WITH A WOMAN OLDER THAN HIM
‪1 YEAR INTO RELATIONSHIP
‪SINCE ESCAPING ETERNAL SINGLEDOM
‪Gosh, it's a celebrity.
‪So cool!
‪-Hello.
‪I'm Noh Jae-yun, the one who came
‪out of the bushes and into a relationship.
‪Let me go ahead and introduce myself.
‪I was a participant in Season One
‪of ‪Better Late Than Single‪.
‪SPEAKER INTRODUCTION
‪NOH JAE-YUN
‪It's not cooperating.
‪BLTS SEASON 1 PARTICIPANT
‪ESCAPED ETERNAL SINGLEDOM (IT'S A MIRACLE)
‪-Miracle.
‪-A miracle?
‪I've only been in one relationship.
‪RELATIONSHIP EXPERIENCE
‪ONLY ONCE (ONGOING)
‪But it's ongoing.
‪And…
‪My qualifications include
‪hard-won real-world experience.
‪"Alpha male"?
‪Well, as a dating expert…
‪I still have a lot to learn.
‪So just think of this
‪as friendly advice from a senior.
‪The first lesson is
‪about the power of honesty.
‪I think many of you
‪have received this question.
‪LESSON 1. THE POWER OF HONESTY
‪"How many relationships have you been in?"
‪Have any of you been asked this?
‪-Yes.
‪-Many times.
‪How do you normally respond?
‪I tell them I'm an eternal single.
‪That's a very good response.
‪But…
‪In my case,
‪when I'd go on blind dates,
‪I'd always lie and say
‪that I'd been in one or two.
‪I was embarrassed to be an eternal single,
‪so I lied.
‪However,
‪I think being honest and saying
‪that you're an eternal single
‪is much better in the long run.
‪Let me explain why.
‪DON'T PRETEND
‪ETERNAL SINGLES GIVE OFF A VIBE
‪You can pretend, but you still
‪give off that eternal single vibe.
‪We give off a vibe?
‪Therefore,
‪just telling the truth
‪could make you more appealing.
‪POWER OF HONESTY?
‪SAY I'M AN ETERNAL SINGLE
‪AN ETERNAL SINGLE IS LIKE A BLANK CANVAS
‪TO PAINT ON TOGETHER
‪This is an advantage
‪of being an eternal single.
‪An eternal single is like a fresh canvas,
‪which means there's plenty of room
‪for new experiences and memories.
‪That's a good mindset.
‪I guess in a way,
‪it's the only advantage.
‪The only advantage.
‪The next lesson is
‪defining the relationship.
‪LESSON 2. DEFINING THE RELATIONSHIP
‪IT'S NOT OFFICIAL
‪UNTIL YOU SAY, "LET'S BE OFFICIAL"
‪It's not official
‪until you say, "Let's be official."
‪This is from my own experience.
‪My girlfriend and I went to cafés,
‪watched movies, and held hands.
‪We did pretty much everything.
‪After about a month,
‪I thought to myself,
‪"We've been dating for a month."
‪But my girlfriend thought,
‪"We've been in a one-month situationship."
‪To make sure you're on the same page,
‪you need to be honest and clear
‪and tell them directly,
‪"Let's be official."
‪That's when your relationship
‪really begins.
‪So on my phone, it says
‪we've been together for 330 days,
‪but it says it's been 300 days
‪on my girlfriend's phone.
‪-A one-month difference.
‪-Gosh.
‪It's been almost a year.
‪The next lesson is
‪about getting prior approval.
‪When you're a new employee,
‪you're not sure how things work,
‪so you need your supervisor
‪to approve everything
‪before you actually do it.
‪Just like that,
‪treat your partner like a supervisor
‪and get their approval first.
‪OUTFIT APPROVAL
‪GET PERMISSION BEFORE YOUR DATE
‪For example,
‪the day before your date,
‪take a photo of your outfit
‪and get approval.
‪Wow.
‪Amazing.
‪This is tough.
‪So this here
‪is what I looked like
‪before getting into the relationship.
‪As you can see,
‪there are five outfits in my closet.
‪One for each weekday,
‪then Saturday and Sunday.
‪-So I owned seven outfits in total.
‪-Gosh.
‪By always asking your girlfriend
‪what style she likes,
‪going shopping together,
‪and getting recommendations,
‪you can change your look like this.
‪BEFORE, AFTER
‪What an it guy.
‪So…
‪You look so cool.
‪As you can see,
‪these aren't expensive clothes.
‪You can look stylish
‪without spending a lot.
‪It's all thanks to my girlfriend.
‪Next is choosing a café.
‪When you go on a date,
‪you may have a meal or watch a movie,
‪but you always go to a café.
‪This means you need to be thorough
‪and check everything.
‪When it comes to restaurants,
‪don't just research online.
‪Figure out the restaurant's vibe
‪on social media
‪and check out people's reactions
‪in the comments first.
‪These are the restaurants
‪that my girlfriend approved.
‪Wow, he's a pro.
‪That's amazing.
‪If you look here,
‪I choose a few popular places in that area
‪through social media first,
‪before looking up their locations online.
‪Then I send these
‪to my girlfriend for her approval.
‪That's what it takes to date.
‪It's not difficult. We just don't do it.
‪So, as long as you're willing
‪to put in some effort,
‪you can all do these things.
‪Do you have a surefire recommendation?
‪A surefire recommendation would be
‪a buffet because it has everything.
‪A buffet?
‪Okay, a buffet.
‪-Buffets are nice.
‪-Yeah.
‪BUFFET
‪Next is choosing a gift.
‪Some people romanticize the idea
‪of planning a surprise gesture
‪after seeing one in a TV show.
‪But that's a little risky
‪because we don't quite have
‪the expertise for that.
‪So on Valentine's Day and such,
‪it might be okay to try a surprise gesture
‪with some convenience store chocolate.
‪But for birthdays
‪or any other special occasions,
‪it's best if you ask your partner first.
‪What special occasions do you celebrate?
‪Well, for now…
‪I only celebrate birthdays.
‪Wait, but didn't he mention
‪Valentine's Day and such?
‪Of course, it would be nice to celebrate
‪Valentine's Day and such if you can.
‪The fourth lesson is
‪that she is a god.
‪This is the one key takeaway
‪from today's seminar.
‪Remember this,
‪and you'll be halfway there.
‪You need to think
‪of your girlfriend as a god.
‪She knows everything about me,
‪and if she's mad, the reason lies with me.
‪Because we're eternal singles, right?
‪Right.
‪If you end up in a fight or disagreement,
‪you must apologize first.
‪For example, let's say
‪a fire broke out at my home.
‪I wouldn't go around
‪looking for the culprit, right?
‪The first thing I'd do
‪is put the fire out.
‪Likewise,
‪you should apologize first
‪and calm her down.
‪Explaining yourself should come after.
‪It's safer that way.
‪There will be plenty of chances
‪to explain yourself later,
‪so it's important to be
‪the bigger person and apologize first.
‪-I have a question.
‪-Yes?
‪You said we should always apologize first.
‪But what if she thinks I'm apologizing
‪to gloss over the situation?
‪What should I do then?
‪For those instances,
‪there are steps to take.
‪STEP-BY-STEP SOLUTION
‪Say, "I'm sorry."
‪Just the words.
‪Then "I'm sorry."
‪Oh, you say it with a gesture.
‪And "I'm sorry."
‪STEP 3. SAY "I'M SORRY" ON YOUR KNEES
‪He's a top-tier instructor.
‪-I know, right?
‪-He's top-notch.
‪Taking these gradual steps
‪will show that you're truly sincere.
‪Another way is
‪to walk her through the situation…
‪ANOTHER WAY TO APOLOGIZE
‪…with the help of ChatGPT
‪-under the table.
‪-I see.
‪You can do what Hyun-kyu did.
‪You kind of get the vibe, but…
‪Hey, come on! Don't do that!
‪Don't read that.
‪You can smooth things over that way.
‪But Jae-yun, what do you say
‪when your girlfriend asks,
‪"What are you sorry about?"
‪The first thing I do is
‪pretend I'm thinking it over.
‪I also glance at her,
‪trying to read her mood,
‪which actually makes her feel bad for me.
‪-It's a useful strategy.
‪-Making her pity you.
‪Only eternal singles can use it.
‪-Oh, I see.
‪-That's right.
‪-So that's why…
‪-It's a weapon.
‪-Excuse me?
‪-Yes?
‪What will you do if your girlfriend
‪watches this show
‪and catches on to your playbook?
‪Good point.
‪That's a good point.
‪She might already know.
‪I'll play it off and say,
‪"Come on, it's for the camera."
‪But you know,
‪I got lucky and met someone
‪who is pretty understanding.
‪She sounds so kind.
‪The next lesson is about
‪how to meet an alpha male.
‪Wow.
‪I should take notes.
‪I hesitated to talk about this
‪because I was afraid of getting backlash.
‪I've noticed that women
‪who have been eternal singles for long
‪tend to look for "the perfect partner."
‪However, it's very hard
‪to meet the perfect partner,
‪so you should…
‪Maybe take it lightly… Wait, no…
‪Maybe don't overthink…
‪I don't think he knows much about this.
‪Is he even reliable?
‪So that would be good.
‪And even if you like someone,
‪if you don't tell them or give them hints,
‪they won't pick up on it at all.
‪So you need to show
‪that you're interested in them.
‪If it's difficult to tell them directly,
‪maybe you can give them
‪some candy or chocolate to drop hints.
‪The next is related to the second point.
‪Instead of not telling them how you feel
‪and suffering alone like I did,
‪try to express your feelings a bit more
‪and be a bit braver.
‪HOW TO MEET AN ALPHA MALE
‪NO PERFECT PARTNER, DROP HINTS, BE BRAVE
‪There are some people
‪who find some situations uncomfortable
‪because they've never dated before.
‪So they end up pushing others away.
‪It would be good to take it easy
‪and give it a try.
‪I feel like that kind of mindset
‪is where a relationship begins.
‪The next lesson is
‪letting go of the fantasy.
‪LESSON 6. LET GO OF THE FANTASY
‪Some people imagine relationships
‪to be like those in K-dramas,
‪where you get crazy butterflies
‪from the smallest physical contact
‪and can read each other's minds,
‪as if you have a telepathic connection.
‪But having the comfort of a close friend,
‪working together
‪to be on the same page,
‪and such are
‪what a real relationship is about.
‪But my own dating life is like a fantasy.
‪Relationships can provide
‪a sense of stability,
‪and that stability builds confidence,
‪which leads to personal growth.
‪My past self
‪was nervous, immature, and clumsy.
‪But through my relationship…
‪STABILITY, SECURITY, EASE,
‪PEACE OF MIND, AND 20 KG
‪…I've gained stability,
‪a sense of security,
‪and peace of mind.
‪I've also gained some weight.
‪Gosh, 20 kg?
‪I hope you can experience
‪the same positive changes
‪through a relationship as I have.
‪Wow.
‪LET'S ESCAPE SINGLEDOM! GANBARE!
‪Wow, ‪ganbare‪!
‪-‪Ganbare‪!
‪The end.
‪Are there any questions?
‪I have one.
‪Compared to being single,
‪what's the best part
‪of being in a relationship?
‪First of all,
‪I've definitely noticed
‪that my level of awareness
‪and social skills have improved.
‪Before dating,
‪I couldn't look people in the eye,
‪or I'd hide in the bushes
‪if someone came near.
‪But now, I stand tall
‪and interact with others confidently.
‪And that makes me realize
‪that my social skills have improved.
‪But nobody here
‪looks like an eternal single at all.
‪-Come on.
‪-Great social skills right there.
‪-Right.
‪Indeed.
‪What a great attitude.
‪I have a question.
‪-Yes?
‪-On the show, you hid in the bushes.
‪Did your girlfriend
‪say anything about that?
‪She said after seeing that,
‪she was a little sad.
‪She didn't expect
‪so many people to simply find it funny,
‪so she felt bad.
‪But for me,
‪I was actually happy
‪that it made people laugh.
‪I don't take things too seriously,
‪and I'm a low-key attention-seeker,
‪so I was pretty happy with it.
‪I have another question.
‪Have you ever asked your girlfriend,
‪"What made you want to date me?"
‪My girlfriend said
‪I looked…
‪a bit down and deflated,
‪so she wanted to care for me.
‪She said I weighed on her mind,
‪-as if I'm her child.
‪-Her maternal instincts kicked in.
‪Write that down.
‪"Trigger maternal instincts."
‪Note to self.
‪-"Trigger maternal instincts."
‪Hurry up and write that down.
‪TRIGGER MATERNAL INSTINCTS
‪Feel free to ask any questions.
‪Personal questions are okay too.
‪Do you think you'll marry her?
‪I've already met my future mother-in-law.
‪That's amazing!
‪Seriously? That's crazy.
‪We've discussed
‪getting married a little bit.
‪I lucked out and met
‪a good person for my first relationship.
‪Let's see…
‪Sorry, I didn't prepare
‪any closing remarks.
‪Let me ask ChatGPT.
‪-Seriously?
‪-Oh, no.
‪So that's how you use it.
‪"Being an eternal single
‪doesn't mean you have a problem."
‪"You're just a bit inexperienced
‪and need more practice."
‪"People who are good at dating
‪weren't good from the start."
‪"They simply learned
‪how to express their feelings."
‪"You're not late to love."
‪"You're just getting started."
‪Thank you.
‪I'll end with my signature move.
‪Here we go.
‪HIS SIGNATURE "BUSHES MOVE"
‪BECAME A LITTLE DULL
‪Are you okay?
‪-Are your knees okay?
‪-Are you okay?
‪-Your knees…
‪-Is he okay?
‪He's leaving just like that?
‪-Where are you going?
‪-Did he leave?
‪-Is this it?
‪I mean…
‪Did he really leave? For real?
‪THE NEXT A/S
‪-Nuna.
‪-Yes?
‪Well, I…
‪I feel so comfortable around you.
‪So instead of ‪nuna…
‪Can I call you Mom?
‪AVATAR BLIND DATE
‪Subtitle translation by:
‪Jenny Kim